Finding Aid for the Christine Sadler Coe Papers
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
- Career in Journalism – Presidential Coverage
  - Johnson, Lyndon B. – 1968 – family (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Johnson, Lyndon B. – 1968 – family (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Johnson, Lyndon B., 1969 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Johnson, Lyndon B., 1970 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Johnson, Lyndon B., 1971 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Johnson, Lyndon B., 1972 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Johnson, Lyndon B., 1973 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Johnson, Lyndon B., 1974 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Johnson, Lyndon B., 1976 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Johnson, Lyndon B. – Memorial Grove, 1976-1977 (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Johnson, Lyndon B. – 1978 – 1982; undated (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Johnson, Lyndon B. – Rebekah Baines Johnson (his mother) (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Johnson, Lyndon B. – biography by Doris Kearns (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - Humphrey, Hubert H. – Campaign, 1968 (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - Nixon, Richard M. – Candidacy (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - Nixon, Richard M. –Inauguration, January 1969 (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - Nixon, Richard M. – Inauguration, January 1969 (Box 14, Folder 20)
- Career in Journalism – Presidential Coverage
  - Nixon, Richard M. – news articles – the arts (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Nixon, Richard M. – The arts, 1971 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Nixon, Richard M. –news articles – family (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Nixon, Richard M. – news articles – Vietnam war (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Nixon, Richard M. – news articles – Watergate (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Nixon, Richard M. – news articles – Watergate (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Nixon, Richard M. – news articles – Watergate (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Nixon, Richard M. – news articles (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Nixon, Richard M. – news articles (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Ford, Gerald R. (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Ford, Gerald R. (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Ford, Gerald R. (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Carter, Jimmy – Inauguration, January 1977 (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Carter, Jimmy – Inauguration, January 1977 (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Carter, Jimmy – news articles (Box 15, Folder 15)
- Career in Journalism
  - Berlin Airlift – 1947 – Map – Germany Zones of Occupation (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Berlin Airlift – 1949 – Trip to Germany – correspondence (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Berlin Airlift – 1949 – Trip to Germany – Draft report by CSC (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Berlin Airlift – 1949- Trip to Germany – contacts (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Berlin Airlift – 1949 – Trip to Germany – booklets (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Berlin Airlift – 1949 – Trip to Germany- reports; press releases (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Berlin Airlift – 1949 – Trip to Germany – military report on German women (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Berlin Airlift – 1949 – Trip to Germany – news articles (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Berlin Airlift – 1949- Trip to Germany – notes (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - State Department Tour of Federal Republic of Germany, July 1964 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - State Department Tour of Federal Republic of Germany, July 1964 (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - State Department Tour of Federal Republic of Germany, July 1964 (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - State Department Tour of Federal Republic of Germany, - July 1964 –Notebook #1 (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - State Department Tour of Federal Republic of Germany – July 1964 – Notebook #2 (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - State Department Tour of Federal Republic of Germany – July 1964 – Notebooks (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - Wives’ Seminar Foreign Service Institute, 1967 (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - Address books (Box 16, Folder 17)
  - Address books (Box 16, Folder 18)
  - Keepsakes (Box 16, Folder 19)
  - Scrapbook items – invitations, programs, etc. (Box 16, Folder 20)
- Writings – Articles (see also scrapbooks and oversize material in flat boxes)
  - “When Mark Twain’s Family was in Tennessee” in Sun Magazine, undated (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - The Nashville Banner, 1930-1936 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - The Nashville Banner, 1930-1936 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - The Nashville Banner, 1930-1936 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - American Foreign Service Journal “ Cornelia Bassel”, December 1938 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - The Standard, Montreal – 1940’s (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - St. Louis Post Dispatch –“Little Girl in the White House”, April 19, 1942 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Egyptian Gazette, July 18, 1948 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Mademoiselle – “To Talk About: a Mind of Your Own’, January – February 1939 (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Mademoiselle – “I Raised My Girl to Be a Soldier”, July 1941 (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Mademoiselle, March 1940-1942 (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Mademoiselle, May 1942 – August 1943 (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - Mademoiselle’s Career Department, October 1942 (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - The Boston Globe – “Mrs. Ives”, July 1952 (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - Clubwoman –“Can 30.000,000 Women be Wrong?”, January 1956 (Box 17, Folder 15)
  - Congressional Record, June 20, 1941; 1942 Congressional resolution on establishing a Women’s Auxiliary reserve in the Navy; Department of State address by Wm Benton, 1946; Department of State Newsletter, February 1968 (Box 17, Folder 16)
  - McCall’s “ The Senator’s Wife Goes Back to School” correspondence, draft, and research notes, 1954 (Box 17, Folder 17)
  - Article on Irina Skariatina (Mrs. Victor F. Blakeslee) for use in event of her death, 1960 (Box 17, Folder 18)
  - Address to the North Carolina Democratic Club, draft with no date; “America the Unknown” note cards for address to Women’s Press Club, Great Britain (Box 17, Folder 19)
  - “McCall’s Gallery of Children in the White House”, May 1962 (Box 17, Folder 20)
  - McCall’s -1952-1969 (Box 17, Folder 21)
  - McCall’s - In and Out of Washington, 1966-1970 (Box 17, Folder 22)
  - McCall’s – In and Out of Washington – 1966-1970 (Box 17, Folder 23)
  - “Mama’s and Papa’s Baby” (Box 17, Folder 24)
  - “The Women Behind Ike” (Box 17, Folder 25)
  - Draft of article on Mamie Eisenhower (Box 17, Folder 26)
  - “Madame Congresswoman” or “Women on the Hill”- draft (Box 17, Folder 27)
  - The Washington Post – advertisement about article by CSC on Fredericksburg (Box 17, Folder 28)
  - The Washington Post, 1937 (Box 17, Folder 29)
  - The Washington Post, 1937-1946 (Box 17, Folder 30)
  - The Washington Post, 1937-1946 (Box 17, Folder 31)
  - The Washington Post, 1937-1946 (Box 17, Folder 32)
  - The Washington Post, 1937-1946 (Box 17, Folder 33)
  - The Washington Post, 1937-1946 (Box 17, Folder 34)
  - The Washington Post, 1937-1946 (Box 17, Folder 35)
  - The Washington Post (Box 17, Folder 36)
  - The Washington Post (Box 17, Folder 37)
  - The Washington Post (Box 17, Folder 38)
  - The Washington Post – “ Mrs. Woodrow Wilson Leads a Quiet Life – But Does It Briskly”, May 22, 1960 (Box 17, Folder 39)
  - The Washington Post – “ Mary Todd Lincoln Most Controversial of First Ladies”, Wednesday January 18, 1961 (Box 17, Folder 40)
  - The Washington Post –“Rachel Jackson’s Funeral Begins Gloomy Era in White House”, January 16, 1961 (Box 17, Folder 41)
  - The Washington Post –“Julia Tyler Had Her Husband Dancing in the White House”, January 17, 1961 (Box 17, Folder 42)
  - The Washington Post –“First, Only Wedding in Blue Room”, January 19, 1961 (Box 17, Folder 43)
- Writings – Articles
  - The Washington Post – “Edith Galt Matched Wilson’s Brilliance”, January 20, 1961 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - The Washington Post – “Grand Dame of Former First Ladies Nears Tenth Decade” October 15, 1961 ( with letter of praise) (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - The Washington Post – “Mrs. Roosevelt Called ‘First Lady of the World’” November 8, 1962 (with letter from Virginia Livingston Hunt) (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - “Claudia Taylor Johnson: A Special McCall’s Report on the First Lady”, March 1964 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Lynda Bird Johnson and trip to Arizona – notes, June 12 – 20, 1965 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Lynda Bird Johnson and trip to Arizona – correspondence, June 12 – 20, 1964 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - “Lynda Bird Uncovers a Skeleton” by Lynda Bird Johnson – typescript copy with CSC’s edits (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - “Pitfalls of College: Some Things I Learned and Wish I had Learned” by Lynda Bird Johnson – typescript copy (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - “The President’s Younger Daughter” (Luci Baines Johnson) – typescript (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - “The President’s Younger Daughter” (Luci Baines Johnson) – research notes and early drafts (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - “The Story Behind Luci Johnson’s Engagement” draft with corrections and interview notes (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - Luci Baines Johnson Nugent – draft and research notes (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - “The First Ladies, Mrs. Wilson and Mrs. Johnson” in Dateline, Vol. Xii, no. 1, 1968 (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - “Mrs. Lyndon B. Johnson” draft of article for McCall’s (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - “Mrs. Lyndon B. Johnson” (Lady Bird) – drafts of article (Box 18, Folder 15)
  - Claudia Johnson (Lady Bird) – drafts of articles re: Seeing the Country with Lady Bird Johnson; interview with Mrs. LBJ re her mother –in- law (Box 18, Folder 16)
  - “Mrs. Lyndon B. Johnson” newspaper clippings about article by CSC, 1964 (Box 18, Folder 17)
  - Lyndon B. Johnson family – research material/newspaper clippings (Box 18, Folder 18)
  - Lyndon B. Johnson family – research material (Box 18, Folder 19)
  - Lyndon B. Johnson family – research material (Box 18, Folder 20)
  - Lyndon B. Johnson family – research material (Box 18, Folder 21)
  - “White House Weddings of Presidential Children – Maria Hester Monroe” draft and research notes (Box 18, Folder 22)
  - “White House Weddings” – drafts of articles (Box 18, Folder 23)
  - “White House Weddings” – drafts and research material (Box 18, Folder 24)
  - “White House Weddings” – research material (Box 18, Folder 25)
  - “She Blazes Trails into Corporate Boardroom” in Christian Science Monitor, October 4, 1971 (article about Patricia Harris) (Box 18, Folder 26)
  - Book reviews by CSC (Box 18, Folder 27)
  - Books - Women of Tennessee: A Record of Their Achievements in the History of the State - related material and correspondence, 1940 (Box 18, Folder 28)
  - “Is This Your Life?” Drama for the Woman’s National Democratic Club, May 25, 1955 (Box 18, Folder 29)
  - “The Kennedys” White House Skit, 1962-63 (Box 18, Folder 30)
  - Books – Eye of the Storm – collaboration with Senator Albert Gore, Sr. – correspondence and research material, 1970 (Box 18, Folder 31)
  - Books – Eye of the Storm – collaboration with Senator Albert Gore, Sr.- contract agreement and other material (Box 18, Folder 32)
    Other articles by CSC in Flat Boxes 35
- Writings –Books –America’s First Ladies
  - Contract, March 13, 1962 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Typescript - complete (Box 19, Folder 2)
- Writings – Books – America’s First Ladies
  - Typescript – pp. 3 – 44 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Typescript –“Who Were the First Ladies?” (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Typescript – “Questions and Answers” (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Typescript – “Abigail Smith Adams…” (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Typescript – “Thomas Jefferson Who Ran a Womanless White House” (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Typescript – “Dolley Madison- The Flamboyant Wife of Great Little Madison” (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Typescript – “Ellen Axson Wilson, and Edith Bolling Wilson” (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Typescript – “Bess Wallace Truman” (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence –publication (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence 1960-61 re: articles on First Ladies (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - Remarks at the Columbia Historical Society, 1965 (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - Reviews (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - St. Johnsbury Woman’s Club Booklet, 1960;Reader’s Guild Program booklet, 1961-62 (Box 20, Folder 14)
  - Transfer of copyright, June 17, 1974 (Box 20, Folder 15)
  - Research material – Martha Washington (Box 20, Folder 16)
  - Research material – Martha Washington (Box 20, Folder 17)
  - Research material – Martha Washington (Box 20, Folder 18)
  - Research material – Martha Washington (Box 20, Folder 19)
  - Research material – Martha Washington (Box 20, Folder 20)
  - Research material – Abigail Adams (Box 20, Folder 21)
  - Research material – Abigail Adams (Box 20, Folder 22)
  - Research material – Thomas Jefferson (Box 20, Folder 23)
  - Research material – Thomas Jefferson (Box 20, Folder 24)
  - Research material – Dolley Madison (Box 20, Folder 25)
- Writings – Books – America’s First Ladies – Research material
  - Elizabeth Kortright Monroe (Mrs. James) (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Louisa Adams (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Louisa Adams (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Andrew Jackson, Rachel and Emily Donelson (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Rachel Jackson and Emily Donelson (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Angelica Van Buren (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Anna Harrison (Mrs. William Henry Harrison) (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Margaret Taylor (Mrs. Zachary) (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Margaret Taylor (Mrs. Zachary) (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Jane Appleton Pierce (Mrs. Franklin) (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - Jane Appleton Pierce (Mrs. Franklin) (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - Buchanan, James – Harriet Lane, niece and hostess (Box 21, Folder 12)
  - Lincoln, Mary Todd (Box 21, Folder 13)
  - Fanny Hayes (Mrs. Rutherford B.) (Box 21, Folder 14)
  - Lucretia Garfield ( Mrs. James Garfield) (Box 21, Folder 15)
  - Chester Arthur, Mary McElroy, his sister (Box 21, Folder 16)
  - Caroline Scott Harrison (Mrs. Benjamin) (Box 21, Folder 17)
  - Ida Saxon McKinley (Mrs. William) (Box 21, Folder 18)
  - Ellen Wilson (first wife of Woodrow Wilson) (Box 21, Folder 19)
  - Edith Bolling Galt Wilson (second wife of Woodrow Wilson) (Box 21, Folder 20)
  - Woodrow Wilson (Box 21, Folder 21)
  - Florence Kling Harding (Mrs. Warren G.) (Box 21, Folder 22)
  - Grace Goodhue Coolidge ( Mrs. Calvin) (Box 21, Folder 23)
  - Lou Henry Hoover (Mrs. Herbert) (Box 21, Folder 24)
  - Anna Eleanor Roosevelt (Mrs. Franklin D.) (Box 21, Folder 25)
  - Anna Eleanor Roosevelt (Mrs. Franklin D.) (Box 21, Folder 26)
- Writings – Books – America’s First Ladies- Research material
  - Anna Eleanor Roosevelt (Mrs. Franklin D.) (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Anna Eleanor Roosevelt (Mrs. Franklin D.) (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Bess Truman (Mrs. Harry) (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Bess Truman (Mrs. Harry) (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Mamie D. Eisenhower (Mrs. Dwight) (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Mamie D. Eisenhower (Mrs. Dwight) (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Mamie D. Eisenhower (Mrs. Dwight) (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Mamie D. Eisenhower (Mrs. Dwight) (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - Jacqueline B. Kennedy (Mrs. John F.) “An Evening with Carl Sandburg”, October 26, 1961 (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - Jacqueline B. Kennedy (Mrs. John F.) (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - Jacqueline B. Kennedy (Mrs. John F.) (Box 22, Folder 11)
  - Jacqueline B. Kennedy (Mrs. John F.) (Box 22, Folder 12)
  - Jacqueline B. Kennedy (Mrs. John F.) (Box 22, Folder 13)
  - Lady Bird( Claudia Taylor) Johnson (Mrs. Lyndon B.) (Box 22, Folder 14)
  - Lady Bird (Claudia Taylor) Johnson (Mrs. Lyndon B.) (Box 22, Folder 15)
  - Lady Bird (Claudia Taylor) Johnson (Mrs. Lyndon B. (Box 22, Folder 16)
- Writings – Books – America’s First Ladies- Research material Box 23
  - Lady Bird (Claudia Taylor) Johnson (Mrs. Lyndon B.) (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Patricia Ryan Nixon ( Mrs. Richard) (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Patricia Ryan Nixon (Mrs. Richard) (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Patricia Ryan Nixon (Mrs. Richard) (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Elizabeth Ann Bloomer (Betty) Ford (Mrs. Gerald) (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Elizabeth Ann Bloomer (Betty) Ford (Mrs. Gerald) (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Rosalynn Carter (Mrs. Jimmy) (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - Rosalynn Carter (Mrs. Jimmy) (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - Rosalynn Carter (Mrs. Jimmy) (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - Nancy Reagan ( Mrs. Ronald) (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - Fashion and portraits (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - First Ladies (Box 23, Folder 12)
  - U.S. Presidents – Inaugurations; homes (Box 23, Folder 13)
  - Second ladies (Box 23, Folder 14)
  - Second ladies – Joan Mondale (Box 23, Folder 15)
  - Would- be First Ladies – Mrs. Earl Warren (Box 23, Folder 16)
  - Would-be First Ladies – Mrs. Harold E. Stassen, 1944-1951 (Box 23, Folder 17)
  - Would-be First Ladies – Mrs. Everett Dirksen (Box 23, Folder 18)
  - Would-be First Ladies – Mrs. Estes Kefauver (Box 23, Folder 19)
  - Would-be First Ladies – Mrs. Paul Douglas (Emily Taft) (Box 23, Folder 20)
  - Would-be First Ladies – Mrs. Robert Taft (Martha) (Box 23, Folder 21)
  - Would-be First Ladies – Mrs. Fred M. Vinson (Box 23, Folder 22)
  - Would-be First Ladies – Mrs. Adlai E. Stevenson (Box 23, Folder 23)
- Writings – Books – Children in the White House –typescript
  - Bound typescript of Children in the White House – copy 1 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Bound typescript of Children in the White House – copy 2 (Box 24, Folder 2)
- Writings – Books – Children in the White House – chapter drafts
  - “Pierce and Buchanan: A Bereaved Father and a Bachelor” – chapter draft (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - “The Lincoln Sons: Free, Happy, and Unrestrained” – chapter draft (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - “Andrew Johnson’s Family: Sons, Daughters, and Grandchildren” – chapter draft (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - “General Grant’s Four: Best and Smartest Children in the World” –chapter draft (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - “Rutherford B. Hayes: Four Sons and a Young Daughter” – chapter draft (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - “James A. Garfield: Mollie and Four Brothers” – chapter draft (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - “Chester A. Arthur: A Tall Son and Pretty Daughter” – chapter draft (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - “Grover Cleveland: White House Marriage and Babies” – chapter draft (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - “Benjamin Harrison: Son, Daughter, and Grandchildren” – chapter draft (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - “Teddy Roosevelt’s Children: Maddest Scramble in White House History” – chapter draft (Box 25, Folder 10)
  - “Taft’s Two Sons and Daughter: He Accepted the Presidency for Them” – chapter draft (Box 25, Folder 11)
  - “ Wilson’s Daughters: a Trio Devoted Completely to Him” – chapter draft (Box 25, Folder 12)
  - “Wilson’s Daughters: a Trio Devoted Completely to Him” – chapter draft (Box 25, Folder 13)
  - “The Coolidge Boys: Both were Bright and Good Looking” – chapter draft (Box 25, Folder 14)
  - “Hoover’s Two Sons: Both were World Travellers at Birth” – chapter draft (Box 25, Folder 15)
  - “FDR and the Kids” – chapter draft (Box 25, Folder 16)
  - “ Franklin D. Roosevelt’s Five: A Daughter and Four Strapping Sons” – chapter draft (Box 25, Folder 17)
  - “Eisenhower – 1953 – 1961” –chapter draft (Box 25, Folder 18)
  - Bibliography – typescript (Box 25, Folder 19)
  - Identification of photographs – typescript (Box 25, Folder 20)
  - Foreword – typescript (Box 25, Folder 21)
- Writings – Books – Children in the White House – typescript drafts for publisher
  - W. H. Harrison (Box 25, Folder 22)
  - Tyler, John (Box 25, Folder 23)
  - Zachary Taylor (Box 25, Folder 24)
  - Millard Fillmore (Box 25, Folder 25)
  - Franklin Pierce and James Buchanan (Box 25, Folder 26)
  - Abraham Lincoln (Box 25, Folder 27)
  - Andrew Johnson (Box 25, Folder 28)
  - U. S. Grant (Box 25, Folder 29)
  - Rutherford Hayes (Box 25, Folder 30)
  - James Garfield (Box 25, Folder 31)
  - Chester Arthur (Box 25, Folder 32)
  - Grover Cleveland (Box 25, Folder 33)
  - Benjamin Harrison (Box 25, Folder 34)
  - Theodore Roosevelt (Box 25, Folder 35)
  - William H. Taft (Box 25, Folder 36)
  - Calvin Coolidge (Box 25, Folder 37)
  - Franklin D. Roosevelt (Box 25, Folder 38)
- Writings – Books – Children in the White House –Publication, Reviews and Research Material
  - Correspondence (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence with Donald MacCampbell Agency (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence with Donald MacCampbell Agency (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence with G.P. Putnam’s Sons (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence with G.P. Putnam’s Sons (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - G. P. Putnam’s – publication contract (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - Publicity schedule (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - Speaking engagements, book fairs, other publicity (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence – advance copies (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - Press notices (Box 26, Folder 10)
  - Press notices (Box 26, Folder 11)
  - Reviews (Box 26, Folder 12)
  - Reviews (Box 26, Folder 13)
  - Reviews (Box 26, Folder 14)
  - Reviews (Box 26, Folder 15)
  - Letters of congratulation (Box 26, Folder 16)
  - Letters of congratulation (Box 26, Folder 17)
  - Research – photographs-correspondence (Box 26, Folder 18)
  - Research – photographs – correspondence (Box 26, Folder 19)
  - Research – correspondence (Box 26, Folder 20)
  - Research – correspondence – The Library of Congress (Box 26, Folder 21)
  - Research material (Box 26, Folder 22)
  - Research material (Box 26, Folder 23)
  - Research material –“Miss Adams in Love” (Box 26, Folder 24)
  - Research notes (Box 26, Folder 25)
  - Research notes (Box 26, Folder 26)
  - Research notebooks (Box 26, Folder 27)
  - Research notebooks (Box 26, Folder 28)
  - Research notebooks (Box 26, Folder 29)
- Writings –Books – Children in the White House - Research Material
  - Washington, George and Martha (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Washington, George and Eliza P. Custis (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - Washington, George and Eliza Custis (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Washington, George and Nelly Custis (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - Washington, George and Nelly Custis (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - Washington, George and Nelly Custis (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - Washington, George and Nelly Custis (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - Washington, George and Nelly Custis (Box 27, Folder 8)
  - Washington, George and Nelly Custis (Box 27, Folder 9)
  - Washington, George and Nelly Custis (Box 27, Folder 10)
  - Washington, George and Nelly Custis (Box 27, Folder 11)
  - Adams, John and descendants (Box 27, Folder 12)
  - Adams, John Quincy (Box 27, Folder 13)
  - Jackson, Andrew and descendants (Box 27, Folder 14)
  - Tyler, John (Box 27, Folder 15)
  - Fillmore, Millard (Box 27, Folder 16)
  - Lincoln, Abraham (Box 27, Folder 17)
  - Lincoln, Abraham (Box 27, Folder 18)
- Writings –Books – Children in the White House - Research Material
  - Johnson, Andrew (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Johnson, Andrew (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Grant, U. S. (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Hayes, Rutherford B. (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - Arthur, Chester A. (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - Cleveland, Grover (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - Harrison, Benjamin (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - Roosevelt, Theodore (Box 28, Folder 8)
  - Taft, William Howard (Box 28, Folder 9)
  - Wilson, Woodrow (Box 28, Folder 10)
  - Coolidge, Calvin (Box 28, Folder 11)
  - Hoover, Herbert (Box 28, Folder 12)
  - Roosevelt, Franklin and children (Box 28, Folder 13)
  - Truman, Harry and daughter Margaret ( Mrs. Clifton Daniel) (Box 28, Folder 14)
  - Truman, Harry and daughter Margaret ( Mrs. Clifton Daniel) (Box 28, Folder 15)
- Writings –Books – Children in the White House – Research material
  - Eisenhower, Dwight D. and grandchildren (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Kennedy, John F. (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - Johnson, Luci Baines – wedding to Patrick Nugent, August 6, 1966 (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Johnson, Lynda Bird – wedding to Charles Robb, December 9, 1967 (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - Johnson, Lynda Bird – wedding to Charles Robb, December 9, 1967 (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Johnson, Lynda Bird – wedding to Charles Robb, December 9, 1967 (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - Johnson, Lynda Bird –wedding to Charles Robb, December 9, 1967 (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - Johnson, Lynda Bird and Charles Robb (Box 29, Folder 8)
  - Johnson, Lynda Bird and Charles Robb (Box 29, Folder 9)
  - Johnson, Lynda Bird and Charles Robb (Box 29, Folder 10)
  - Johnson, Lynda Bird and Luci (Box 29, Folder 11)
  - Nixon, Richard M. and children (Box 29, Folder 12)
  - Ford, Gerald and children (Box 29, Folder 13)
  - Descendants of Presidents (Box 29, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence and research material - miscellaneous (Box 29, Folder 15)
- Writings – Books – unpublished –America’s First Princess: Nelly Parke Custis Lewis
  - Publication correspondence (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Research material – letters (Box 30, Folder 2)